Guide to the Hansen Glove Corporation records, 1927-1954 and undated RL.11733
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hansen Glove Corporation records
1927-1954 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hansen Glove Corporation
RL.11733
2.0 Linear Feet
Hansen Glove Corporation was a manufacturer of gloves and mittens based in Milwaukee, Wis. Collection includes black-and-white photographs, print advertisements, transcripts of meetings, published booklets, sales literature, catalogs and color sample guides. Advertising materials may be the work of the Klau-Van Pietersom-Dunlap agency (later part of Hoffman York). Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Hansen Glove Corporation was a manufacturer of gloves and mittens based in Milwaukee, Wis. Founded by brothers J.E. and Oscar C. Hansen, hat and fur merchants, as Cream City Hat Co. 1871; moved to Milwaukee 1880; ended partnership 1890 with Oscar Hansen taking over the hat and glove operations; renamed O.C. Hansen Mfg. Co. 1901; Hansen Glove Corporation 1930.
Klau-Van Pietersom-Dunlap agency founded Anthony Van Pietersom and Gustav Klau 1906; Walter Dunlap joined 1908; acquired by Hoffman York 1973.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Hansen Glove Corporation records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2019.
Related Materials
Related material may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
American Catalin Corporation salesman's sample book
Gene Federico papers
Pioneer Tailoring Co. salesman's sample case
Collection Overview
Collection includes black-and-white photographs, print advertisements, transcripts of meetings, published booklets, sales literature, catalogs and color sample guides. Advertising materials may be the work of the Klau-Van Pietersom-Dunlap agency (later part of Hoffman York). Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- United States -- History; Sales promotion; Selling; Commercial catalogs; Klau-Van Pietersom-Dunlap; Hoffman York (Firm); John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- Hansen Glove Corporation, 1927-1954 and undated; 1
  - Advertising Merchandising Program, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Animated Gesture, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Appointment cards, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Challenge of a Glove, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Charm Magazine cover highlight, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Coach and Four model, undated (Box 1)
  - Color guide, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Color guides, 1940-1941 (Box 3)
  - Color Key to Costume Loveliness, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Color Portrait of a Gentlewoman, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Fall color guide, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Fall and winter color guide, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
  - Full-Dress Fall, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - Glove shampoo mailer, undated (Box 1)
  - Guide to Smart Spring Color Harmony, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Hansen Glove News, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Hushed Hues, 1947 (Box 1)
  - In Color Cahoots, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Jubilee Colors (Hansen 75th anniversary), 1946-1947 (Box 1)
  - Keepsake Colors, 1945-1946 (Box 1)
  - Know and Sell These Hansen Fashion Points, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Le Gant de France (Gant Guignie, illustrated by Maurice Brenier; in English), undated (Box 1)
  - Newspaper mat service, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Not Apart but a Part of the Clothes of Today, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Occasion Designed, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Personality Gloves, 1950-1951; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Personality Gloves Give You a Plus, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1)
  - Point of purchase display, Hansen/Lux tie-in, undated (Box 1)
  - Postcard, approximately 1944-1945 (Box 1)
  - Print advertisements (not Hansen), 1952 and undated (Box 3)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes: Harms of California; Hendan Mannish Shirts
  - Rich Harvest, 1947-1948 (Box 2)
  - Sales meeting notes, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Sell Gloves of Fashion by Hansen--Glove department bulletin board information chart, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Spot merchandiser display brochure, undated (Box 2)
  - Spring color guide, 1953-1954; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Spring and fall color guide, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Spring and summer color guide, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Success Story, undated (Box 2)
  - Suppressed Excitement, 1943 (Box 2)
  - The Art of Glove Making (National Association of Leather Glove Manufacturers), 1927 (Box 2)
  - The Biography of a Glove (National Association of Leather Glove Manufacturers), undated (Box 3)
  - Triumphant Colors Keyed to Wartime Costumes, approximately 1942 (Box 2)
  - Vogue color and fabric sample chart, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Zephyr vendor catalog description, undated (Box 2)